《訴訟雙雄》前情提要
我這么早起床  是為了考慮
I got up early, so I could figure out
這里有沒有哪樣家具我能接著用
if there's anything around here that I could stand living with.
-你要搬過來一起住嗎  -如果你還邀請我的話
- You want to move in together? - If the offer still stands.
開玩笑嗎
Are you kidding me?
奎汀跟我還是夫妻時  你就跟他上床了
You slept with Quentin while he was married to me.
我那時問你
I asked you back then
我們分開前  你們是不是就有一腿了
if anything had started before we were separated.
你說沒有
You said it hadn't.
那是因為我不想傷害你
'Cause I didn't want to hurt you.
敬嶄新的合伙關系
Here's to your new partnership.
我替你付了買入股份款
I fronted your buy-in.
你怎么能這么做
How could you do that?
我把它當作浪漫之舉
I did it as a romantic gesture.
是啊  美女或許愛演浪漫電影
Yeah, well, pretty woman may have been a romantic movie,
但朱莉亞·羅伯茨還是個妓女
But Julia Roberts was still a hooker.
你知道奎汀有肌萎縮側索硬化癥多久了
How long have you known Quentin had A.L.S.?
一開始就知道
From the beginning.
那你知道他為了自救  在實驗結果上造假
And how long have you known Quentin falsified
好讓藥早點上市這件事多久了
trial results to get the drug on the market?
-他沒撒謊  -但你撒謊了
- He didn't lie. - But you did.
而我愛他  我還能怎么做
I love him. So what else could I do?
我是認真的  斯科特
I am in this, Scottie.
好的
Okay.
我也是
So am I.
認為邁克·羅斯上的是一所很差的法學院
I think Mike Ross went to a subpar law school
而且一直在用謊言掩蓋這個事實
and has been lying about it the whole time.
給哈佛打電話要一份他的成績單復印件
Just call up Harvard and ask for a copy of his transcript.
吉拉德教授的法律職業道德課
Professor Gerard's legal ethics class,
你聽說過誰得了"A+"嗎
did you ever hear of anybody ever getting an a-plus?
沒有  他就是以給分不超過"A"出名的
No, he's famous for never giving higher than an "A."
法律職業道德  吉拉德教授
你為什么這么開心啊
Well, what are you so happy about?
今早上你沖澡時我用泡沫布做了拖鞋
I made bubble-wrap slippers this morning while you were in the shower.
我還特地告訴過你  泡沫布是用來包盤子的
I specifically told you the bubble wrap is for the dishes.
我還做了頂帽子
I also made a hat.
好吧  我要跟個十歲小孩同居了
Okay, I'm moving in with a ten-year-old.
你愛我的
And you love me.
是啊
I do.
我在想
Hey, I was thinking,
我們的床要怎么辦啊
what are we going to do about our bed?
我們已經有兩張床了
We already have two.
是啊
I know, but, yeah, we do.
但你不覺得新的開始該買新的床嗎
But don't you think a new beginning deserves a new bed?
這真是太可愛了
That...is incredibly sweet.
十歲小孩能想到真不賴哈
Yeah, not bad for a ten-year-old, huh?
你想要什么樣的床
What kind of bed were you thinking?
我們今晚試過之后挑一個唄
Whichever one we pick out after we test them tonight.
你想好了什么特定的測試嗎
And did you have any particular test in mind?
現在有了
Well, now I do.
不過店家估計不會允許我們那么測試吧
See, I don't think the store is gonna let us run that kind of test.
是啊  有道理
Yeah. No, you're right.
我們今晚出去之前在家測試一下吧
We should probably just test ours before we go out tonight.
你干什么啊
What are you doing?
路易剛剛可能看到我們了
I think that Louis might have just seen us.
那又怎么樣啊
Come on, what's the difference?
我們要同居了
We're moving in together.
我們是不是別再保密了
I think it's time we stopped keeping it a secret.
但是保密還挺好玩的嘛
But keeping it a secret is sort of fun.
還性感
And sexy.
我是最贊成性感的了  我可是做了
And I am pro sexy-I mean, I did make
泡沫布拖鞋和帽子呢
those bubble-wrap slippers and hat after all,
說來好笑
which is funny, 'cause...
因為那不叫性感  只是好玩
that's not sexy, it's just fun.
-算是吧  -算是
- It's something. - Something.
我還給你做了
I made you some too.
達娜·斯科特  資深合伙人
哈維  她至少還要一周才會回來呢
Hey, Harvey, she won't be back for another week,
你現在還是先別開瓶了
so I don't think you need to start drinking just yet.
你是要取笑我  還是幫我想想
You want to make fun, or you want to help me
這東西該放哪
figure out where to put this?
威士忌酒
A bottle of scotch?
你就不能給她買點更貼心的禮物嗎
You couldn't get her anything more personal?
-她喜歡威士忌  -那是你
- She likes scotch. - You like scotch.
她喜歡我  因此
She likes me. Therefore...
你何不附上張卡片
Why don't you just attach a card that says,
寫上"歡迎  隨便你是誰  資深合伙人"
"Welcome, generic senior partner"?
這可是一萬二的威士忌
This is a $12,000 bottle of scotch,
而且是全球僅有的三瓶之一
and this is one of three left in the world.
這怎么能算是"隨便"呢  這表示...
That doesn't say generic, that says--
你是我最近買下的三樣
You're one of three very expensive things
貴重物品之一
I recently purchased.
入股的事我們談開了
We worked it out about the buy-in.
那這只會揭開瘡疤
And this is gonna un-work it out.
說來好笑
You know, it's funny.
先說這不夠貼心  現在又變成有特殊意義了
First it was too generic. Now it's special.
你什么意思
What are you saying?
你覺得你不是不滿意我選擇的禮品
I don't think you have a problem with my choice of gift.
我覺得你是對接受禮物的人有意見
I think you have a problem with my choice of recipient.
如果不是我  你覺得斯科特能來這兒嗎
Do you think scottie would even be here if it wasn't for me?
是不能
No, I don't.
哈維  我希望你能如愿
Harvey, I want this for you.
我也希望你們能好好的  我只是想
I want it to work, and I'm just trying to--
確保我不搞砸了
Make sure I don't screw it up.
我們都知道那是早晚的事
Well, we both know you're gonna screw it up.
我只是想讓那天盡量晚點來
I'm just trying to delay that as long as possible.
你確定嗎
You sure about this?
那瓶酒就是我秘書日時自己買禮物的原因
That bottle is the reason I buy my own present for secretary's day.
-還有秘書日呢  -有啊
- There's a secretary's day? - There is.
而且你可慷慨了
And you're very generous.
你好嗎  邁克
How you doing, Mike?
激動嗎
Are you excited or what?
激動什么
Excited about what?
沒收到我的電郵嗎
Didn't you get my email?
收到了
Oh, there it is.
讀讀吧
Why don't you read it?
算了
Oh, actually, you know what, never mind.
我就直接告訴你吧
I'll just let you know what it says.
很棒的  你一定喜歡
It's so great. You're gonna love it.
我請了亨利·吉拉德周五過來
It says I invited Henry Gerard here
做講座
to give a lecture this Friday.
好啊
That's great.
你根本不知道那是誰吧
You don't even know who he is, do you?
亨利·吉拉德教授嘛
Professor Henry Gerard,
法律道德課教材的作者
author of the definitive text in legal ethics
在該部門任了20年的主席
and chair of the department for the last 20 years.
我當然知道他
Yeah, I know who he is.
那你還記得你在他班上拿的分數嗎
And do you also remember what you got in his class?
A+不容易忘啊
It's pretty hard to forget an a-plus.
是啊  忘記不可能的分數的確不容易
Yeah, it's pretty hard to forget a grade that never happened.
吉拉德從不給人A+
No one gets an a-plus in Gerard's class.
也沒人能背下他書里的一整章
Yeah, well, no one can recite an entire chapter of his book from memory.
-除了我  我做到了  -胡說
- But I can and did. - Bullsh--.
你沒拿到A+  因為你從沒上過那門課
You never got an a-plus because you never took his class.
那是必修課  路易  我當然修了
It's a required class, Louis. Of course I took it.
除非你就沒去過哈佛
Not if you never went to Harvard.
路易  別傻了
Louis, that is insane.
我有哈佛的成績單
I have a transcript from Harvard.
我有哈佛的學位  因為
I have a degree from Harvard. That's because I--
慢著  我猜猜  因為你去過哈佛嗎
Wait, let me guess. 'cause you went to Harvard?
你瞧  邁克  問題是
See, Mike, here's the situation.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
我也不想給吉拉德打電話問他
And I don't want to call Gerard up and ask him
因為我不想讓我的公司被世人嘲笑
'cause I don't want the world laughing at my firm.
但如果周五的時候  他沒有走過來
But if he doesn't walk up to you on Friday
對你說  邁克·羅斯  我的得意門生
and say, "Mike Ross, my beloved student
我記得你  你是唯一
who I remember, because he's the only one
我給了A+的學生
I ever gave an a-plus to,"
那我就知道你是在撒謊了
Well, then, I'm gonna know you're lying.
如果你還不肯承認
And if you still don't come clean,
那我就啟動正式調查
I'm gonna launch a formal investigation,
不管那會不會讓事務所難堪
whether it makes my firm look bad or not.
別發瘋了  沒什么可調查的
This is crazy. There is nothing to investigate.
那我寧可像個瘋子一樣揪出冒牌貨
Well, I'd rather risk looking crazy to root out an impostor
也不能冒險讓那個冒牌貨毀了我在乎的一切
than to risk letting that impostor poison everything that I stand for.
結束了  邁克
It's over, Mike.
我盯上你了
I'm on to you,
我要揭露你
and I'm gonna expose you
撒謊卑賤的真面目
for the lying piece of filth that you are.
你吐完了
Don't forget to rinse your mouth out
別忘記漱口
after you're done throwing up.
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
翻譯   草草
翻譯   青椒
翻譯   Reginamoon
翻譯   七個柚子醬
翻譯   王大可
翻譯   貓咪賜我速死
人人影視
YYeTs.com
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為
訴 訟 雙 雄
第三季   第十二集
翻譯   親愛的小飯
校對   月月
你以前說過  如果路易知情了  我們會知道
Do you remember when you said if Louis knew, we'd know?
他知道了
He knows.
他做了什么
What did he do?
時間軸  小式
他要請亨利·吉拉德來做講座
He's bringing in Henry Gerard to give a lecture.
那又怎樣
So what?
這會是你第一次受他講座的摧殘
It'll only be the first time you've had to suffer through it.
時間軸  憑陵新月
他帶他來是因為他看到
He's bringing him in because he saw
我在他課上拿過A+
I got an A-plus in his class.
什么  沒人能在吉拉德課上拿到A+
What? No one gets an A-plus in Gerard's class.
后期  冰冰愛尖尖
-這就是問題所在  -該死的
- Welcome to the problem. - God damn it.
唐娜  進來
Donna, get in here.
你叫唐娜干什么
Why are you calling Donna?
因為是她發現路易已經知道
Because she's the one who found out that Louis knows
哈佛大學檔案庫里沒有你
you don't have a file in the Harvard file room.
總監  swears
你怎么知道
How do you know that?
因為路易的新女朋友
Because Louis's new girlfriend
是管哈佛大學檔案庫的
is the queen of that file room,
而且她還把他留在了那里
and she left him alone in there.
你們怎么沒跟我說一下呢
You guys didn't think to mention this?
我以為我處理好了
I thought I handled it.
她確實處理了
She did handle it.
她讓他去查看你的成績單
She sent him to sniff out your transcript.
結果沒想到法律倫理學課
Only she didn't realize you gave yourself
你居然給自己打了A+
an A-plus in legal ethics.
不是我打的  是羅拉·詹森打的
I didn't give it to myself. Lola Jensen did.
誰給你打的分并不重要
I don't give a shit who gave it to you,
問題在于分數不是吉拉德教授打的
unless it was professor Gerard, which it wasn't.
修這門課的人有多少
How many people take the class?
也許  邁克可以混跡在人群中
I mean, maybe Mike will just be another face in the crowd.
路易請他過來
Louis is bringing him here
是為了看他是否認得自己的得意門生
to see if he embraces his star student.
混跡在人群中完全是個餿主意
The worst thing I can do is just be another face in the crowd.
一定要確保他來不了
We need to make it so that he doesn't come.
不行
It's not gonna happen.
他從來不會取消約定
The man doesn't back out of commitments.
他最喜歡的名言是"法律的運轉
His favorite quote is "For the law to work,
離不開人的言行如一"
there must be honor in one's word."
-這是誰的名言  -他自己的
- Who's he quoting? - Himself.
自戀狂
Pompous prick.
他根本沒參與過實戰
Guy never practiced a day in his life,
就敢寫法律社會倫理學方面的書
thinks he can write the book on real-world ethics.
好吧
Okay.
我不恐慌  但是我們該怎么辦
I'm not panicking, but what are we gonna do?
你暫時先靜觀其變
Right now, you're gonna sit tight.
那你們怎么做
And what are you going to do?
我覺得應該告訴杰西卡
I think it's time to tell Jessica.
我們得談談
We need to talk.
-確實  -你知道了嗎
- We do. - You know?
不知道  但不管是什么  先等等
No, but whatever it is, it can wait.
這個事情等不了
This isn't something that can wait.
奎汀去世了
Quentin died.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
我知道肌萎縮側索硬化癥不容樂觀
I knew A.L.S. wasn't gonna be a picnic.
我也知道總有這么一天  但是...
And I knew this was coming, but it doesn't--
如果你需要一段時間調整  我可以照顧這里
Look, if you need some time, I can manage things here.
哈維  我很想休息
The truth is, Harvey, I'd take it.
但麗薩正在路上
but Lisa's on her way in
要跟我們討論奎汀的遺囑
to discuss Quentin's will with us.
我們
Us?
奎汀讓我們來擔任他財產的遺囑執行人
Quentin named you and I co-executors of his estate.
你是她丈夫的前妻
You're her husband's ex-wife.
我覺得麗薩不會把這件事當成公事
I doubt Lisa sees this as just business.
肯定不會
No, I can't imagine she does.
你能把這件事完全當公事嗎
Can you see this as just business?
你不喜歡她
You don't like her,
也不信任她  而且這非常理所當然
you don't trust her, and you have good reason for both.
奎汀要求我這樣做
Quentin asked me to do this.
也許他讓我也當遺囑執行人是有原因的
Maybe he gave you a co-executor for a reason.
你是說他在給我機會退出嗎
You're saying he was giving me an out?
不  我只是說我會陪著你
No, I'm just saying that I'm here,
所以你不用勉強自己
and you don't have to do this.
哈維  他給了我責任
Harvey, he asked me,
我不會讓他失望
and I'm not going to let him down.
邁克  你不能坐以待斃
Mike, you can't just wait for the ax to fall.
我沒有坐以待斃  我做了準備
I didn't just wait. I armed myself.
充分了解了吉拉德和他的課程信息
I learned everything there is to know about Gerard and his class.
哈維說得對  這貨真是自戀狂
Harvey is right. This guy is a prick.
他讓所有學生必須讀他的書
He makes everybody read his books
但根本不會考里面的內容
and then doesn't even test on them.
好吧  但是這種準備不夠
Okay, but arming yourself isn't enough.
我們得做點別的
We need to actually do something.
哈維讓我靜觀其變
Harvey told me to sit tight.
所以我就靜觀其變
That's exactly what I'm gonna do.
是嗎  可那是因為哈維并不危險
Right, that's because Harvey's life isn't on the line.
我們很危險
Ours is.
我們
Ours?
邁克  我選擇跟你同居
Mike, I am not moving in with you
不是因為我要找新住處
because I need a new place to live.
好吧  那我們應該怎么辦
Okay, so what do you think we should do?
怎樣才能讓他相信你上過哈佛大學
What's gonna make him believe that you went to Harvard?
我的成績單  畢業證書
Well, if my transcript, diploma,
還有一份只有哈佛畢業生能拿到的工作
and the job you can only get by having attended Harvard
這樣都不夠的話  我也不知道了
aren't enough, I'm not really sure what is.
肯定有點什么話可以說吧
Well, there's got to be something you can say.
瑞秋  你也知道路易這人
Look, Rachel, you know Louis.
我越努力否認
The more I try and deny it,
他就越會追根究底
the more he's gonna come after me.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
真是難以置信
I can't believe this.
他這人就這樣
He is not gonna be happy
一定要證明自己是對的才滿意
until he has a signed full confession proving he was right.
沒錯
You're right.
那我就讓他滿意
And that's exactly what I'm gonna give him.
來吧
Come on.
你還真是直截了當
It's all fairly straightforward.
公司不應該受影響
The company shouldn't be affected.
這份遺囑進行法律認證事
Tim can continue with the day-to-day
蒂姆可以繼續過日常生活
while this works its way through probate.
可是日常生活會發生變化
Well, the day-to-day's going to change.
-為什么  -普萊森提出了一個交易
- How so? - We have an offer from Pryzen.
你想賣掉公司嗎
You want to sell the company?
我想接受這個交易
I want to accept an offer.
你動作真快
Well, that was fast.
你說什么
Excuse me?
杰西卡的意思是
What Jessica is saying is
普萊森還真是見縫插針
Pryzen didn't waste any time swooping in.
不  我的意思是
No, what I'm saying is,
再進行法律認證之前
before we authorize anything,
得先確定這樣是否有好處
we need to evaluate if this is even a good idea.
沒必要
I don't see why.
我們的法律顧問認為這樣可以  我同意
Our general counsel thinks it's a good idea, and I agree.
而且公司的股份大部分由我繼承
And I'm the one who's inheriting the majority of the company,
-所以我有權決定  -不  并不是這樣
- so it's my decision. - Actually, it isn't.
你在說什么
What are you talking about?
我的工作是確保奎汀能夠得償所愿
My job is to see that Quentin's wishes are fulfilled.
你是在暗示  你比我更了解他的遺愿嗎
Are you implying that you know his wishes better than I do?
我是在暗示  他去世不到一周
I'm implying he's not dead a week,
你就要把他的名字從公司除掉  永不提起
and you want to strip his name off the door and into oblivion.
我是要讓他窮極一生
What I want to do is put the drug
研發出的藥品
that he dedicated his life to
交給有資源去完成的公司手里
in the hands of a company with the resources to finish it.
當他為這樣的公司工作時
And I was there
我還在他身邊
when he worked for companies like this.
而他討厭這些公司
And he hated them,
這也是后來他出去自己干的原因
which is why he went out on his own.
你在他身邊
You were there?
我聽說的可不是這樣
Well, that's not how I heard the story.
行了  我們不是來吵架的
All right, we're not doing this.
你想要賣掉你的股份嗎
You want to sell your shares?
沒人說你不可以
No one's saying you can't.
但我們有責任對它進行評估
But we have a responsibility to evaluate it.
還記得你說過你會試著和解的
Remember when you said you'd try to be conciliatory?
我從沒說過那句話
I never said that.
你應該這么說的
Well, you should have,
因為你絕對沒辦法不帶私人感情色彩
'cause you sure couldn't keep the personal out of it.
我不覺得他們會伙同所有員工
I didn't think they were gonna come at me
一起逼我
with all that stuff.
他們沒要逼你
They weren't coming at you.
他們只是帶來了一個提議
They were coming with a proposal.
你真的覺得那個提議是憑空而來的嗎
Do you really think that offer came out of thin air?
我覺得他們有可能是等著攻其不備
I think it's possible they waited to pounce.
也有可能是
It's also possible
在奎汀還躺在病床上時
that Lisa and Tim put this in motion
麗莎和蒂姆就開始找買家了
while Quentin was lying in his hospital bed.
那假如真是這樣呢
And what if they did?
這是我們該管的事嗎
Is that really our business?
杰西卡  我知道這對你而言有多困難
Jessica, I understand how hard this is for you,
但這個藥才是他的心血遺作
but his legacy is this drug.
而不在于是制成此藥是否在他名下
It's not about whose name is on the company that makes it.
你是說你贊同麗莎嗎
You're saying you agree with Lisa.
我現在說的正是我之前試圖告訴你的
I'm saying to you now what I tried to tell you before.
你肯定會帶私人感情色彩  而我不會
This is personal for you. It's not personal for me.
所以在我們有進一步行動之前
So before we take another step,
讓我先評估一下這個提議吧
let me evaluate this offer.
你說的沒錯
You're right.
我騙了你
I lied to you.
我騙了所有人
I lied to everyone.
我是作弊才進了這里
I cheated to get here,
假如你把我推到亨利·吉拉德面前
and if you put me in front of Henry Gerard,
他是不會記得我的
he's not gonna remember me.
因為你從來沒上過他的課
'Cause you never took his class.
因為我從來沒去上過他課
Because I never went to his class.
因為你從來沒上過哈佛
'Cause you never went to Harvard.
-不是這樣的  -放屁
- That's not true. - Bullshit.
路易  拜托  聽著
Louis, please, look,
我知道你完全有權利生我的氣
I know you have every right to be angry with me.
我沒生氣
I'm not angry.
氣憤只是一閃而過
Angry is just a flash in the pan.
但我對你的痛恨卻是綿綿無絕期的
My outrage is here to stay,
而我會消滅一切威脅我律所的毒瘤
and I will obliterate any infection threatening my firm.
我不是你認為的毒瘤
I'm not the infection you think I am.
唯一造了假的就是那個A+
The only thing that's bullshit is that A-plus!
你說什么
What?
路易  我上過哈佛的  我...
Louis, I went to Harvard. I...
我只是改了我的成績
I just changed my grade.
你覺得我會相信你這套說辭嗎
You expect me to believe that?
我一直是我上過的每所學校里
I have always been the smartest kid
最聰明的學生
at every school that I went to.
高中  大學  在哈佛的前兩年
High school, college, the first two years of Harvard,
我不用學都能拿A
I'd get "A"s without studying.
我不去上課都能在所有考試里拿滿分  但是...
I'd ace every test without going to class, but--
但是到了第三年
but that third year...
你得上吉拉德的課
You had to take Gerard.
我能背下他的書
I could memorize his books,
但是他的考試卻和他的書無關
but his tests weren't about his books.
是啊  他的考試是和他的講座有關
Yeah, they're about his lectures.
-期末考試...  -我掛了
- The final exam-- - I failed it.
我去他辦公室求他再給我一次機會
I went to his office to beg for a second chance.
他從來不會再給一次機會
He doesn't give second chances.
但我總得試試看啊
I had to try.
他不會答應的
He wouldn't do it.
他不在辦公室
He wasn't there.
我進了他辦公室  里面沒有人
I got to his office. It was empty.
他的電腦就開在那里
His computer was just sitting there,
登在主系統上
logged in to the main system.
他正準備把成績提交上去
He was about to submit his grades.
在他回來前我只有幾秒鐘的時間  所以
I only had a few seconds before he came back, so...
我決定自救一下
I decided to save myself.
不對  你是決定給自己一個A+
No, you decided to give yourself an A-plus.
不是的  路易
No, Louis.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
也許你以后再也沒辦法相信我了
You might not be able to believe me about anything else ever again.
但你得相信這個
Believe this.
你無法想象我是有多希望能重來一遍
You have no idea how much I wish I could do it over again,
若能重來  我會正正當當
because this time, I would do it right.
我會去上每一堂課  去聽每一個講座
I would go to every class, and I would attend every lecture,
我會盡力汲取哈佛所提供的一切
and I would feast on what that place has to offer
比所有人都認真
like no one ever has.
但是你第一次就沒做好
But you didn't do it right the first time.
你作弊了
You cheated,
而如今你又指望我幫你逃過一劫
and now you're looking at me to help you get away with it.
不是的  路易
No, Louis--
滾出我的視線
Get out of my sight.
真是驚喜啊
What a surprise.
路易  拜托了  我只是想...
Louis, please, I just want to--
我知道你想干什么  你想要說服我
I know what you want to do-- you want to lobby me
為了某個膽大包天的人
on behalf of someone who had the audacity--
我愛他
I love him.
什么
What?
我們準備同居了
We're moving in together,
我們準備一起開始一段生活
and we're starting a life together.
瑞秋
Rachel--
而我之所以告訴你這個
And I'm telling you this
是因為我知道他干了什么
because I know what he did
但我仍然愛著他
And I still love him.
好吧  問題來了
Okay, here's the problem.
我不愛他
I don't.
-路易  -瑞秋...
- Louis. - Rachel...
我尊敬你
I respect you.
我關心你
I care about you.
但這不是針對你
But this isn't about you.
這是針對邁克和他對我做的事
This is about Mike and what he did to me.
你知道嗎
You know,
你叫他做你助手的那個晚上  他來找我了
he came to me the night that you asked him to be your associate.
我要他跟著你干
I told him to go with you.
為什么
Why?
因為他說過他和你有一種聯系
Because he said he had a connection with you
那種聯系他從沒和哈維有過的
that he's never had with Harvey.
-他這么說過  -是的
- He said that? - Yes.
你們對法律有著共同的熱愛
Your shared love of the law.
-是的  這是我告訴他的  -我知道
- Yeah, I told him that. - I know.
而我和你也有同樣的聯系
And I have the same connection with you.
瑞秋  你是想叫我去...
Rachel, you're asking me to--
路易  他做這件事不是針對你
Louis, he didn't do this to you.
他這么做是為了能從事
He did it so that he can practice the thing
我們都熱愛的事業
that we all love.
假如你不放過他的話
And if you don't let it go,
他就再也不能從事這個了
he's never gonna be able to practice it again.
謝謝你獨自前來
Thank you for coming alone.
我很高興能幫上忙
I'm happy to help,
但我和杰西卡是一邊的
but Jessica and I are a team,
而你單獨見我并不能改變這一點
and asking to see me alone doesn't change that.
在這過程中我不會撇開她
I'm not gonna cut her out of the process.
這難道不是她想對我做的事嗎
Isn't that what she's doing to me?
她試圖取消交易
She's trying to kill the sale.
這封信上可不是這么說的
That's not what this letter says.
我不是律師  但我也不蠢
I'm not a lawyer, but I'm not stupid.
上面說一切接洽都必須經過皮爾遜-斯佩克特
It says all communication goes through Pearson Specter.
這個不會影響交易的
This doesn't kill the deal.
但這會告訴他們
It tells them that
他們一直在和沒有實權的人協商
they've been negotiating with people with no power at all.
不  這會告訴他們  他們必須得
No, it tells them they have to
在進行雙向談判而非單向
negotiate with two entities instead of just one.
這能使我們更占上風
It gives us more firepower.
你想怎么樣  麗莎
What do you want, Lisa?
我想知道你為什么沒有在上面簽名
I want to know why your signature isn't on that letter.
因為我們達成一致了
Because we came to a consensus,
她代表我們簽了名
and she signed it on both our behalves.
-我不相信你  -隨便你
- I don't believe you. - I don't care.
如果你不能接受我們通知買家
And if you can't handle us notifying the buyer
說正在評估這筆交易
that we're evaluating this sale,
那我就該質疑
then it makes me question
到底是誰被蒙蔽了
whose judgment is really clouded.
恕我失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me,
背著我的合伙人來見你  我已經見夠了
I'm done meeting behind my partner's back.
不是說好讓我評估這筆交易嗎
What the hell happened to letting me evaluate this offer?
我讓你來評估
I am letting you evaluate the offer.
你想用這封信把交易攪黃了
You sent this letter to kill the deal.
我是想用那封信幫你拖延時間
I sent that letter to buy you time.
杰西卡  你以我的名義簽了一份
Jessica, you put my name on a document
你明知我絕不會同意的文件
you knew I wouldn't support.
你站在麗莎那邊了  你想賣
You are on lisa's side. You want to sell.
這與麗莎無關  我壓根就不在乎
This isn't about lisa, and I don't give a shit
這間公司到底賣不賣
whether this company is sold or not.
但這關乎你我的關系
This is about you and me
還有我們經營事務所的方式
and how we're going to run this firm.
我們不是談過這點了嗎
Didn't we just have a conversation about that?
是啊  談過了
Yeah, we sure did.
牽扯到斯科特的時候
And when it had to do with Scottie,
你洋洋灑灑地說了一通信任
you gave me a big speech about trust,
說我得相信你所做的一切
about how I had to trust you had rational reasons
都有合理的理由
for what you were doing.
-這是兩回事  -沒錯
- This is different. - Exactly.
這次不是我的私事
This time it's not personal for me.
而是你的
It's personal for you.
而且你違反了自己定下的規矩
And you're not playing by your own rules.
這筆交易是個錯誤  哈維
This deal is wrong, Harvey.
而且無論如何  我還是執行合伙人
And like it or not, I'm still the managing partner.
在這個案子上并不是
Not on this.
你只是共同執行人
On this, you're a co-executor,
別再用以我的名義簽署任何文件
and you're not putting my name on any more letters.
我建議你收拾好心情
So I suggest you get your head on straight
理性地看待這筆交易
and look at this deal rationally.
如果你做不到
And if you can't do that,
我建議你別再插手了
I suggest you step aside.
杰西卡  你愛過他
Jessica, you loved him.
我知道你很痛苦  她也是
I know you're hurting. So is she.
不管你過去跟她有什么恩怨
Whatever your history with her,
她也一樣感受得到
so is she.
這么晚還沒下班
You're here late.
助理的生活不就這樣
The life of an associate, right?
是啊  我記得
Ah, yeah, I remember.
我也曾待在這個房間
I used to live in this room,
面對成堆的工作
work piled all around me,
靠咖啡和傳遞文件過日子
surviving on coffee, delivery,
不眠不休
and no sleep.
我一直在想
And the whole time, wondering,
伙計  將來能有輕松的日子嗎
"Man, is it ever gonna get any easier?"
-結果有嗎  -沒有
- Does it? - No.
但你還是喜歡這種生活
But you still love it.
你也是
And so do you.
不然你就該回家陪著愛你的人
Or else you'd be home with the woman who loves you,
而不是在這度過漫漫長夜
not spending your night here.
-你知道了  -她來見過我
- You know. - She came to see me.
我本來覺得不能原諒你
I didn't think I could forgive you.
可她設法…
But then somehow, she...
讓我明白了我可以
made me realize I could.
路易  我真不知如何感謝你
Louis, I don't know how to thank you.
別別別  先別謝我
Oh, no, no, no. Don't thank me yet.
你這么做傷害的并不是我
I'm not the one you did this to.
什么意思
What are you saying?
意思就是你這么做傷害了亨利·吉拉德
I'm saying you did this to Henry Gerard.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
而我無權替他決定是否追究
And it's not my place to let it go for him,
所以你得向他坦誠一切
which is why you're gonna have to come clean to him.
你也說過
You said it yourself
吉拉德不會給人第二次機會
Gerard doesn't give second chances.
他給不給機會要由他決定
What he does or doesn't do is up to him.
那是他的權力  邁克
That's his right, Mike,
因為你對不起他
as the person that you wronged.
可他不需要知道我對不起他
Yeah, but he doesn't have to know that I wronged him.
聽我說
Listen to me.
你說過如果有機會重來  你會做對的事
You said that if you had it to do over, you'd do it right.
我正是在給你這樣的機會
I'm giving you that chance.
好好把握
Take it,
否則我只能親自出手了
or I'm gonna have to take it for you.
你來這兒干什么
What are you here to do now,
連我家都要搶嗎
take my house away from me?
我是來找你談談的
I'm here to talk.
上次我們談的時候  你說
Well, the last time we talked, you pretty much said
我不夠關心我丈夫因此沒尊重他的意愿
I don't care about my husband enough to honor his wishes.
上次我們談的時候
The last time we talked,
我犯渾了
I was an asshole.
原諒我蹩腳的法語
Pardon my French.
我不在乎你的法語如何
I don't mind your French.
我后來意識到  或許我
It's come to my attention that I may have let
被之前的恩怨左右了對情勢的判斷
our history affect how I'm handling this situation.
有意思
It's funny.
哈維也讓我意識到了這點
Harvey brought that same thing to my attention.
所以…
So...
告訴我
tell me this.
你為什么想賣
Why do you want to sell?
知道我為什么
Do you know why
在肌萎縮性側索硬化試驗的事上撒謊嗎
I lied about those A.L.S. trials?
因為就算鋌而走險我也要繼續這個研究
Because I was desperate for the research to continue.
不過無所謂了
But it didn't matter.
麗莎
Lisa.
他本不該死的
He wasn't supposed to die.
他本來也活不了這么久
He wasn't supposed to live as long as he did.
我們在努力延長他的生命
We weren't trying to prolong his life.
努力研發藥物來治好他
We were trying to find a cure.
可我們沒能做到
And we failed.
你從來沒在乎過錢
You never cared about the money.
我唯一在乎的錢就是為他研發藥物的錢
The only money I cared about is the money to find the cure,
可我們沒有那么多錢    普萊森有
and we don't have the resources. Pryzen does.
但他們已有一種肌萎縮性側索硬化藥了
But they already have an A.L.S. Drug.
那不如我們的有效
It's not as good as ours.
但卻能賺取更多利潤
In profit margin, it's better.
這就意味著沒什么能阻擋他們
Which means there's nothing to stop them
去買你的公司  讓你的藥不見天日
from buying your company, burying your drug,
并以此牟取暴利
and making a fortune.
你想說什么
What are you saying?
我想說你沒有讓他失望
I'm saying you didn't fail him,
但我很清楚那種以為你讓他失望了的感覺
but I know how it feels to think that you did.
有個辦法能確保我們都不會
And I have a way to make sure that neither one of us
再有這樣的感覺
feels that way again.
所以你那偉大的計劃弄巧成拙了
So your great plan backfired.
哈維  對不起
Harvey, I'm sorry.
我不需要你說對不起
I don't need you to say I'm sorry.
但下次我讓你靜觀其變的時候
But the next time I tell you to sit tight,
-你得給我答應  -好
- I need you to say you will. - Okay.
很好  因為我現在
Good, because the next time
就要讓你靜觀其變
I tell you to sit tight is right now.
等等  你打算怎么做
Wait, what are you gonna do?
我要坐飛機去波士頓
I'm getting on a plane to Boston.
去干嘛
And doing what?
等我回來你就知道了
I'll let you know when I get back.
為什么要去波士頓
Why are you going to Boston?
要去見一下馬庫斯  他有了點麻煩
I have to see Marcus. He's in trouble.
我能幫上忙嗎
Anything I can do?
不用  我自己能行
No, I'll handle it myself.
既然你要走  我需要你幫我起草
Since you're leaving, I'm going to need you to draft
一些關于出售桑茲制藥的文件
some language for the Sainz pharmaceutical sale.
所以你同意出售了
So you're in favor of it now?
也不完全是
Well, not exactly.
但我聽了你的話  去見了麗薩
But I heard what you said, and I went to see Lisa.
她和我達成了一致
She and I are on the same page.
你有時間聽聽我們的計劃嗎
Do you have time to hear what the plan is?
我相信你
I trust you.
你需要我起草什么內容
So what do you need me to draft?
我需要你起草一個
I need you to draft a provision
能保證普萊森完成開發該藥物的條款
that guarantees Pryzen will finish developing that drug.
好的
Consider it done.
他不是去見他弟弟是吧
He's not seeing his brother, is he?
不  不是
No, he's not.
- 想詳細聊一下嗎  -不太想
- Care to elaborate on that? - Not particularly.
你是說我應該相信他嗎
You're saying I should trust him.
我是說我相信
I'm saying I do.
我本想問問你還好嗎  看來我知道答案了
I'd ask how you're holding up, but I can see the answer.
不太好
Not well.
關于你這些天所經歷的事情
I can only imagine what these last couple of days
我只能試圖想象
have been like for you.
但我想跟你說  一切都會好的
But I'm telling you, it's gonna be okay.
-你怎么知道  -我就是知道
- You don't know that. - Yes, I do.
-如果好不了呢  -那我們就完了
- But what if it's not? - Well, then we're screwed.
但這種情況不會發生的
But that's not gonna happen.
聽著  唐娜
Look, Donna.
我已經很努力的讓自己勇敢了
I am trying so hard to be brave.
但如果路易發現了 邁克所有的秘密呢
But what if Louis ends up finding out everything about Mike?
如果他真的揭發了他  他被抓起來了呢
What if he ends up exposing him and he actually gets arrested?
如果他真的
What if he actually--
天哪
God.
瑞秋
Rach,
邁克發現我們公司的一個合伙人
Mike found out that one of our partners
下令執行了多起謀殺案
ordered multiple murders.
哈維說他會處理的
Harvey said he'd fix it.
兩天后  那個合伙人就進了監獄
Two days later, that partner was in prison.
史蒂芬是個罪犯  但這件事只是學術上的
Stephen was a criminal. This is an academic.
他沒做什么錯事
He hasn't done anything wrong.
哈維之所以很擅長自己的工作
Well, what makes Harvey great at his job is he knows
就是因為他知道每個人都做了一些錯事
that everybody has done something wrong.
就連國內最受尊重的職業道德教授都一樣嗎
Even the most esteemed ethics professor in the country?
他們看起來越干凈
The cleaner they look,
藏起來的污點就越多
the more dirt they've swept under the rug.
我要說的是  哈維會走過去
I'm telling you, Harvey's gonna walk in there,
然后找到那些污點
he's gonna find the lump,
亨利·吉拉德絕對不會知道他要面對什么
and Henry Gerard is not gonna know what hit him.
每周三晚  八點到十點
Wednesday nights, 8:00 to 10:00,
總是如此準時
it's like clockwork.
一致性并不是什么可怕的東西
Consistency is nothing to be feared.
我沒有害怕  我還指望著它呢
I wasn't afraid of it. I was counting on it.
斯佩克特先生
Mr. Specter.
吉拉德教授
Professor gerard.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
您還像我當時在這里時一樣
Looks the same as the last time I was here.
對你我就不能這么說了
Can't say you look the same as the last time you were here.
是的  你可以
Yes, you can.
看來你還想以前一樣謙遜
I see you're as humble as ever.
過幾分鐘我們就知道是誰謙遜了
we'll see who's humble in a few minutes.
順便正式說一句
And for the record,
您對我將來會變成什么樣子的判斷是錯的
you were wrong about how I'd turn out.
我知道你變成了什么樣子
I know how you turned out.
紐約最愛和解的律師
More settlements than any other lawyer in New York.
紐約結案效率最高的律師
More closings than any other lawyer in New York.
在現實世界中  和解只是達成目的的
And settling is what it takes to get the job done
一種手段
in the real world.
我知道你所需要的那些手段
I know what it takes for you to do what you do,
這種人生中的妥協讓步
and compromising your way through life
根本不是法律的精神
is no way to go about the law.
看來你還跟以前一樣自大
I see you're as pompous as ever.
你來這里的目的是什么  斯佩克特先生
What did you come here for, Mr. Specter?
-我來請你幫個忙  -我不會答應的
- I came to ask for a favor. - The answer is no.
你還不知道是什么事呢
You don't even know what it is.
但我知道是你在請求我
I know you're the one who's asking.
我就知道你會這么說  所以帶了這個來
I figured you'd say that, which is why I brought this.
我不認為勒索可以叫做幫忙
I don't consider blackmail a favor.
我很懷疑如果董事會看到了這些東西
I doubt the trustees will care about semantics
還會不會在意措辭
when they see that.
我也懷疑董事會有沒有東西可以看
well, I doubt the trustees are gonna see anything at all.
因為那個信封里肯定裝滿了白紙
Because that envelope is full of blank paper
或者你的干洗收據
or your dry cleaning receipts.
你覺得我是在嚇唬你
You think I'm bluffing?
我確定你是
I know you are.
如果你認為信封里面的東西毫無意義
If you think that envelope is meaningless,
為何不打開看看呢
why don't you go ahead and open it?
你面無表情的功力真是大增
Your poker face has gotten much better,
這點我同意
I'll give you that.
練習得多了  你懂的
A lot of practice, you know,
人生中的妥協讓步
compromising my way through life.
你知道了
You know.
我知道了  你高談闊論
I know. And you talk a big game,
但你其實也只是一個普通人
but you're just as human as everyone else,
你這自以為是的混蛋
you smug son of a bitch.
你想讓我做什么
What's your favor?
找個理由取消你周五的行程
Find a reason to cancel your trip on Friday.
如果之后路易·利特再試圖聯系你
And if Louis Litt ever tries to contact you after that,
不要接他的電話
don't take his call.
-看起來很簡單  -確實簡單
- Seems easy enough. - It is.
晚安  吉拉德教授
Have a good night, Professor Gerard.
但問題是  斯佩克特先生
Here's the problem, Mr. Specter.
我不只是高談闊論  我也會身體力行
I don't only talk a big game. I walk it.
職業道德從來不是指不犯錯誤
And ethics is not about never doing anything wrong.
而是指如何做選擇
It's about making choices.
我絕不會讓你替我選擇
And I'm not going to let you make my choice for me.
所以你想怎樣請隨便吧
So go do whatever you're gonna do,
我是不會取消行程的
but I'm not canceling my trip.
你沒搞定
You didn't get it done.
你怎么知道
How'd you know?
因為我知道如果成功了你會打電話給我的
Because I know you would call to tell me if it's okay.
但你沒有  所以應該是失敗了
And you didn't call, so it's not okay.
那你怎么還這么冷靜
Then why are you so calm?
因為你教我了很多
Because you've taught me enough to know
以至于我知道這一切都會沒事的
that it's going to be okay.
-不會的  -什么
- It's not. - What?
不會沒事的  我不知道我們要怎么辦
It's not gonna be okay. I don't see what we're gonna do.
什么叫你不知道我們要怎么辦
What do you mean you don't see what we're gonna do?
你是哈維·斯佩克特
You're Harvey Specter.
那又怎樣呢
What's that supposed to mean?
那意味著就算有槍指著你的頭
It means there's a gun pointed at our heads.
我們也能有146種辦法解決它
There's 146 things that we can do.
我們只需要齊心協力想個辦法出來
We just have to put our heads together and figure it out.
不然你以為我這一晚上
What the hell do you think I've been doing
都在干什么
all goddamn night?
路易抓住我們的把柄了  他不會放手的
Louis has us, he's not gonna let it go,
我們也沒有什么辦法能夠阻止他了
and there's nothing we can do to stop it.
-一定還有辦法  -沒有了
- There has to be something. - There isn't.
我拒絕那么想
Well, I refuse to believe that.
我才不在乎你怎么想
I don't give a shit what you believe.
早點想通吧  我不是超人
Get it through your head. I'm not superman.
我失敗了  我不知該怎么辦
I failed, and I don't know what to do.
邁克
Mike.
蒂姆  我以為我是和麗莎見面
Tim, I thought I was meeting with Lisa.
而我以為你們會公開見面
And I thought you were above board.
我看你讀過了我們的修正案了
I see you've read our amendment.
你起草的條款中有一條
You drafted a provision
如果他們不支付一億美元以完成制藥
that if they didn't spend $100 million finishing that drug,
他們將另付一億作為賠償
they'd have to pay us an extra $100 million.
我所起草的這條條款
I drafted a provision to see
是要確保他們說到做到
if they'd put their money where their mouth is.
你就在做你一直想做的
What you did was what you always wanted to do--
就是毀了這交易
tank this deal.
他們虛抬價
They pulled the offer.
他們要壓價
They yanked the offer.
那這筆交易就沒有開始的必要了
Then the deal wasn't worth anything to begin with.
你讓奎汀簽的那份
What wasn't worth anything
讓你的人代替我成為遺囑執行人的文件
was the document you had Quentin sign
才是一文不值
making you executor instead of me.
我沒讓奎汀簽什么文件
I didn't have Quentin sign anything.
好吧  你說沒有就沒有吧
Well, maybe you didn't have him sign it,
但我可知道他什么時候簽了的
but I know when he signed it,
而且這東西攔不住我的
and it's not gonna hold up.
當然會攔得好好的
It'll hold up just fine.
我們走著瞧
We'll see.
這是傳票
This is a subpoena.
所以下次我們再見
So the next time we have this conversation,
你就得實話實說了
you'll be under oath.
民事訴訟聽證會傳票
他到底什么意思
What exactly is he claiming?
他說奎汀任命我為執行人時
He's saying Quentin wasn't competent
并沒有判斷能力
when he made me executor.
那讓他說去吧
So let him say it.
我看來一點問題也沒有
I don't see where there's a problem.
不  你看出來了
Yes, you do.
不  我沒有
No, I don't.
只要站在聽證席上作證
Just get up on the stand and testify that Tim
證明蒂姆根本就是瞎說
doesn't know what he's talking about.
但事實并非如此
But he does.
奎汀知道他想要什么
Quentin knew what he wanted.
他們不會向我尋求答案
They're not going to ask me that.
他們只會來問我他的身體狀況
They're going to ask me about his condition.
我見過他了  麗莎
I saw him, Lisa.
我知道他是個怎樣的人
I know what he was like.
奎汀知道他想要什么
Quentin knew what he wanted.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
他用了藥物  講話都困難
He was also medicated, could barely speak,
病痛纏身
and he was in a lot of pain.
但你不必講那些東西
But you don't have to say those things.
我在法庭上不得不實話實說
I'm going to have to swear to this under oath.
如果任你為執行人是沒有法律效力的
If making you executor wasn't legally valid,
那他這么做的時候你為什么不說
then why didn't you say so when he did it?
因為我覺得那樣不夠有挑戰
Because I didn't think it would be challenged.
但對于有些無關緊要的事
And thinking something might not hold up
在腦子里想想  緘口不提
and keeping that thought to myself
和在法庭上撒謊可不一樣
is not the same as lying about it under oath.
好吧  這是鉆模糊概念的空子
Well, those are some fuzzy damn lines.
概念不是我定的  現實就是如此
I didn't make them. They came with the job.
你就要這么推翻他的一切嗎
You're gonna undo everything he's ever worked for.
大概吧
Maybe.
但我和你目的一致
But just because you and I want the same thing
并不意味著我會為此做偽證
doesn't mean that I'm willing to perjure myself to get it.
求你了
Please.
你說過你不想再讓他失望了
You said you didn't want to fail him again.
你沒失敗
You didn't fail.
你不必這樣安慰我
You don't need to make me feel better.
我不是想安慰你
I'm not trying to make you feel better.
只是告訴你事實
I'm just telling you the truth.
你沒有失敗  因為
You didn't fail because...
我們一直就在爭取時間
we were always playing on borrowed time.
-邁克  -哈維
- Mike. - Harvey.
如果沒有你我不可能得到這些
I wouldn't have any of this without you.
我覺得是時候讓我獨當一面了
I think it's time I cut your exposure.
你不必如此
You don't have to do that.
反正都是要毀于一旦了
It's all gonna come crashing down anyway.
我會去找路易
I'm gonna go to Louis.
我會辭職
I'm going to resign,
我會求他放過這整件事
and I'm gonna beg him to let this whole thing go.
那我和你一起去
Then I'm going with you.
哈維
Harvey,
特雷弗把我的秘密告訴杰西卡時
when Trevor went to Jessica with my secret,
我覺得自己被背叛了
I felt betrayed.
我失去了我世上最好的朋友
I lost my closest friend in the world.
我知道你不會承認
And I know you don't like to admit it,
但我們確是朋友
but we're friends.
而我不會背叛我的朋友
And I'm not gonna betray my friend.
我以前可煩這種事了
I used to hate this kind of thing.
哪種事
What kind of thing?
客座講座  哈德曼以前逼著我們聽完
Guest lectures. Hardman used to make us sit through them.
除了之后他還會進行測驗
Except he gave tests afterwards.
是啊  如果你沒過  就要被罰檢閱文件
Yeah, and if you didn't pass, you got stuck on doc review.
該死的哈德曼
Goddamn Hardman.
你還記得羅賓森的案子嗎
You remember the Robinson case?
當然了
Sure do.
八萬份文件  準備了兩年
80,000 documents, two years of prep,
在法庭上奮戰了五個月
and five months in court.
而在庭審前的那個周五
And the friday before trial started,
他要我們倆把所有東西校對一遍
he assigned you and I to proof everything.
你溜走了
You blew it off.
而你幫我掩護
And you covered for me.
你把我們兩人份的都做了  然后交了
You did your half and mine, then turned it in.
他當場就會炒了你的
He would've fired you on the spot.
沒錯  但我好好的
Exactly, and I'm here
因為你沒有出賣朋友
Because you didn't sell out a friend then,
但你就要出賣了
but you're about to now.
-邁克嗎  -我
- Mike. - Me.
你是朋友
Friend?
路易  可能我永遠不會說出口
Louis, I may not ever say it,
但那并不代表我們不是朋友
but that's not because we aren't.
我們是朋友  你知道的
We are. You know it.
我知道
I know it.
我只是不愛說出來
I just don't like to say it.
上回我問你  你還說  別逼我
Last time I asked you, you said, "Don't push it."
你知道我的意思是答應了
You knew I meant yes.
我知道
I did.
-所以是邁克告訴你的  -是的
- So Mike told you. - He did.
你怎么說的
What'd you say?
那無所謂
Doesn't matter.
我的底線是  我會原諒他
Bottom line is I forgave him because I don't care
我才不關心那些破紙上說什么呢
what some stupid piece of paper says.
而我也希望你能原諒他
And I want you to forgive him too.
哈維  我原諒他了
Oh, Harvey, I did forgive him.
我只是沒法為他掩飾
I just can't cover it up for him.
你就為我向哈德曼打了掩護
You covered it up with Hardman for me.
那個周末你的所為
What you did that weekend
和他對吉拉德教授做的不一樣
is not the same as what he did to Professor Gerard.
相同之處就是吉拉德教授和哈德曼一樣
What's the same is Hardman wouldn't have let it go,
不會就這么算了
and Gerard won't let it go.
你讓邁克坦白真相
You make Mike confess,
無異于將他的人生徹底毀掉
you might as well throw his life down the toilet.
哈維  他背叛的不僅是我們
Harvey, he didn't just betray us.
-他這是違法  -是的
- He betrayed the law. - He did.
-這是不對的  -對啊
- That's not right. - It isn't.
但是原諒是無關對錯的
But forgiveness isn't about right and wrong.
路易  我知道你尊重法條
Louis, I know you value the letter of the law,
但法條包含的精神呢
but what about its spirit?
因為邁克的身上
Because Mike embodies
比我們倆都更體現法律的精神
that spirit more than either one of us.
你說過我們是朋友
You said we're friends.
朋友是永遠不會要求我這樣做的
A friend would not ask me to do this.
是不會  路易
No, Louis.
作為朋友  如果你不這樣做  我也不會怪罪你
A friend just won't hold it against you if you don't.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
上帝助你  你能發誓你說的是真話
Do you swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
句句屬實  無半句假話嗎
and nothing but the truth, so help you god?
我發誓
I do.
但在我們開始之前  我要先聲明一下
But before we start, I'd like to make a statement.
我來這里說出真相
I am here to tell the truth,
但我希望你們明白
but what I want you to understand
真相也是主觀的
is that truth is subjective.
真相就是真相
The truth is the truth.
不  法律就是法律
No. The law is the law.
我們可以定義合法的邊界在哪里
We can define where a legal line is.
我說的是真相
I'm talking about the truth.
但真相卻復雜得多
The truth is much more complicated.
根據法律條文的字面義
By the letter of the law,
奎汀·桑茲也許不一定具有相應行為能力
Quentin Sainz may or may not have been competent.
我沒法兒說這些百分百是真的
I can't say what's true with 100% certainty.
路易·利特
法學博士
我不知道
I just don't know.
但我能確定的是
But what I can say with certainty
奎汀·桑茲信任我  把他最重要的利益
is that Quentin knew what he was doing
交由我處置時  他是理智的
when he trusted me to look after his best interests.
你是怎么知道的
How do you know that?
因為我了解他
Because I knew him.
因為有的人身上不具備有
Just because someone can't check off everything
某些清單列出的一切要求  并不意味著
on the list that's required to be competent doesn't mean
他們做什么都比我們這些人差勁
they aren't better at whatever they do than the rest of us.
奎汀·桑茲是個天才
And Quentin Sainz was an amazing man
擁有天才的頭腦
with an amazing mind.
如果他現在在這里
And if he were here right now,
比起聽其他人說
I'd still listen to him on any subject
我更想聽他說任何事情
sooner than I'd listen to anybody else.
非常感人
That's all very touching,
但我們不是來談真相的
but we're not here to talk about the truth.
我們是來處理法條的
We're here to deal with the letter of the law.
根據法律條文
Have you never met someone who by the letter of the law
有人無法做他們想做的事
shouldn't be able to do what they do,
-但他們克服了困難  -法官大人
- who beat the odds? - Your honor--
我們談的是一個人的一生
We are talking about a man's life.
我們談的是他的遺產
We are talking about his legacy.
我不認為那些事情不如
And I dispute that those things are less important
法條更重要
than the letter of the law.
法官大人  今天應該怎么做已經非常清楚了
Your honor, what has to happen today is very clear.
您必須消除這樁不公之事
You have to undo this injustice.
是的  重點就是公平
Yes. This is about justice.
但問題不在于奎汀·桑茲委托我作遺囑執行人時
But the issue isn't whether Quentin Sainz was competent
是否具有行為能力  而在于
when he made me executor, but rather,
如果他具有行為能力  這是不是他的意愿
would it have been his intent to do so if he were.
這個男人一生都撲在一項事業上
This man dedicated his life to one thing,
關于他如何保護那項事業的詳細情況
and the circumstances surrounding how he decided
不是問題所在
to protect that thing is not the question.
這是法律問題  皮爾森女士
It's a question of law, Ms. Pearson.
不  這是關于做正確決定的問題
No, it is a question of doing what is right.
路易
Louis.
你來這里做什么
What the hell are you doing here?
-我  -我告訴你要在午餐前
- I-- - I told you I needed
搞定卡瑞爾的歸檔文件  但你沒搞定
the Carell filings by lunch-- you didn't get that done,
所以現在你不能來聽這門課
so now you don't get to listen to this lecture.
你不能來聽我們關于法律職業道德的巔峰對話
You do not get to listen to this titan talk about legal ethics.
你讓我覺得很惡心
You know something, you make me sick.
快幫我個忙  向他道歉
So do me a quick favor and tell him you're sorry
然后趕緊滾開
and get the hell out of here.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我接受你的道歉
I accept your apology,
但我沒什么委屈的
but I'm not the aggrieved one here.
路易才委屈
Louis is.
路易
Louis...
-我很抱歉  -行了
- I'm sorry. - Yeah.
他不是我的人  走吧
It's not my pony. Come on.
駁回關于撤除杰西卡·皮爾遜作為遺囑執行人的動議
Motion to remove Jessica Pearson as executor denied.
你說得對
Well, you were right.
奎汀·桑茲心中有數的
Quentin did know what he was doing.
我知道到最后
I know how hard it must have been...
有多艱難
at the end.
我很慶幸奎汀擁有你
I'm glad Quentin had you.
我也很慶幸他擁有你
I'm glad he had you too.
他手下留情了
He let it go.
我聽說都搞定了
I heard it all worked out.
毫無疑問啊
Never a doubt.
我為你準備了個禮物
I've got a present for you.
蒂芙尼
Tiffany.
"D.J.S"
"D.J.S."
這是為斯科特準備的禮物
This is a present for Scottie.
也就是為你準備的禮物
Which makes it a present for you.
-把這個放進她的辦公室吧  -太好了
- Let's put this in her office. - Great.
跟你那瓶特別貴的威士忌放在一起吧
We can put it next to your overpriced bottle of scotch.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
真是個很棒的禮物啊
So it was a great gift.
現在確實是
Now it is.
準確的說  她的中間名是維多利亞
For the record, her middle name is Victoria.
不對  不是
No, it isn't.
那是什么
What is it?
拜托  她沒告訴過我
Please, she never told me.
朱莉
Julie?
-真的嗎  -杰西
- Seriously? - J essie?
-天吶  -喬伊嗎
- Oh, my god. - Joy?
-你太可悲了  -還是珍妮
- You're pathetic. - Jenny?
不會告訴你的
Not telling.
這樣恐怕不太好吧
I don't think this is a good idea.
我不管
I don't care.
他們能怎么著  炒了咱倆嗎
What are they gonna do, fire us?
邁克  過去六年
Mike, I haven't left before 5:00
我從未五點前下班
in the past six years.
那就更有理由去了
All the more reason to do it.
你想干什么
Now what do you want to do?
看個電影  吃個晚飯  再去喝兩杯
See a movie, grab dinner, get a drink?
我只想回家
I just want to go home.
好  那就回家
Yeah. Let's go home.
最近好像老有人來啊
People seem to keep coming in here lately.
我想聽點音樂
I needed to hear some music.
喝點威士忌
And drink some scotch.
這兩樣怎么能不配在一起呢
How often do you really do one without the other?
坐過去
Move over.
你搞定你的大麻煩了嗎
Did you take care of your Marcus problem?
暫時解決了
For the time being.
很好
Good.
其實問題并不是我之前說的那個
It wasn't really a Marcus problem.
我知道
I know.
你想聽實話嗎
You want to hear the truth?
今晚別說了
Not tonight.
所以我開始才沒有告訴你
That's why I didn't tell you in the first place.
我知道
I know.
人人影視
YYeTs.com